welcome everyone
my name is subhankar dey and i am a
faculty with icc foundation
today our topic for discussion is
introduction to etiquette
under the module etiquette and grooming
today's objective
is to make you all understand what is
etiquette and why it is important to us
let us check some scenarios from our day
to day life
i want you all to give a thought to all
these images
starting with the first image it shows a
differentiation between an animal
and a human being you will find an
animal moving from one place to another
completely unorganized not maintaining
proper behavior
compared to a human being which looks
quite presentable
and quite responsible thus we can
differentiate a human being
from an animal to tell you more
there are people who have the habit of
burping loudly
in public places this looks very very
bad
and is disrespectful for others
while some people have the habit of
speaking loudly over the phone in public
places
which is quite disturbing for others
there are people who have the habit of
eating
untidally and keep their things
in an untidy and disorganized manner
do you think these things are accepted
in the society
never would you like to follow the same
or try to be somebody who is more
presentable
and more responsible being someone who
is always
approachable to others what do you think
of course i would like to be somebody
who is presentable
responsible and is always approachable
for others
i hope your concept on etiquette is
somewhat clear by now
to move forward let us watch a video
welcome back i hope you have observed
the video
carefully and have understood what the
video is trying to tell you
what i have understood from this video
is that there were
certain behaviors that were annoying
i want to ask you some questions how you
can avoid
being annoying to others how you will
present yourself
well in front of others ask yourself
these questions
you know the answer for all these
questions are by maintaining
proper etiquette wherever you go
i believe you all have understood how
maintaining
a positive etiquette will help you to
have a positive image
of you in front of the society
this takes us to the next topic for our
discussion which is
importance of etiquette in our
day-to-day life
etiquette is how you present yourself
according to the environment
just think how you behave at your home
at your workplace at your college
or at your friend's place are all
different
why because every situation every
environment
every surrounding has different way of
behavior
etiquette refers to a set of guidelines
that controls the way
a person should behave in the society
you cannot sit in an inappropriate
manner in front of the guest
at your home but when the guests are
left
you can sit in a comfortable manner even
if it
is not proper
we human beings are social animal and it
is very important for us
to behave in an appropriate manner in
the society
etiquette helps us to differentiate
between an animal and a human being
in terms of behavior it helps us
to earn respect and appreciation in the
society
will you respect somebody who is
irresponsible
and shows in proper behavior never
always remember the way you interact
with your senior your parents your
friends
your co-workers speaks a lot about your
personality
and your upbringing to conclude
a man's manner or etiquette are a mirror
in which
he shows his picture what he is made of
etiquette inculcates a sense of loyalty
and trust in a person it makes a person
more responsible
and mature it makes a person to value
relationship thank you
keep learning